

## **NWOKOMA EMMANUEL**

Software (Android & Web) Developer

+2348158576171

<u>nwokomaemmanuel@gmail.com</u>, <u>nwokomaemmanuel@octofi.com.ng</u> <u>nwokoma@gigabytedevelopersinc.com</u>

https://linkedin.com/in/emmanuelnwokoma https://github.com/enwokoma

## Summary

Experienced in designing and developing software for business solutions.

A software developer with experience in designing and developing programs using the latest and most appropriate technology.

As someone who specializes in both frontend and backend development, I am very experienced with all stages of the software development cycle for dynamic projects. I am very well-versed in numerous programming languages including: JAVA, Kotlin, PHP, Javascript, Bash and VB.NET. Alongside all this, I also have a strong background in management and customer relations, successful at marketing techniques, knowledgeable about digital media platforms and deadline-oriented editing. Through these qualities, I have confidence in my ability to facilitate positive change and collaborative effort.

### Skills

- LANGUAGES: Kotlin, JAVA, PHP, Golang, Bash, VB.NET, Javascript
- APPLICATIONS: Android Studio, PHPStorm, PyCharm, WebStorm, MS Visual Studio, Eclipse.
- APPLICATION SERVERS: JBoss, Apache Tomcat, Nginx
- OPERATING SYSTEMS: Windows, Unix, Linux
- DATABASE SYSTEMS: SQL Server, MySQL, Ingres, PostgreSQL
- Project management
- Strong decision maker
- Complex problem solver

- Creative design
- Innovative
- Service-focused
- Strong organizational and prioritization skills along with keen attention to detail.
- Good interpersonal and organizational skills, with an ability to work both independently and collaboratively.

### Experience

**Lead Developer -** 02/2016 to 07/2019 SHOPPING SAMRAT, India *(remote)* 

Lead developer for the development of ecommerce store, shoppingsamrat.com.

#### Responsible for:

- Developing of the website using OOP PHP.
- Supporting further releases developed in ASP.
- Adapting and adjusting graphic packages from other regions.
- Working closely with the writer producers and editors.
- Strong creative and conceptual vision and excellence in Typography.

# Senior Software Developer and Chief Technical Officer - 08/2016 – 12/2020 OJALAWA, Lagos (Nigeria) – remote, onsite

A senior executive (CTO) with sole responsibility for managing the technological requirements of ecommerce startup (Ojalawa), currently developing its online store, ojalawa.com.

Ojalawa is a startup, an online food market dedicated to the supply of groceries around Lagos State.

### Responsible for:

- Complete development of the website using Magento.
- Development of a mobile application for Android.
- Leading development team for framework designing.
- Developing project concepts and maintaining optimal workflow.
- Carrying out quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability.

### Highlight:

• In spite of very tight schedules and limited resources, the e-store was fully developed from scratch and was online for an extensive beta testing.

# Co-founder and Chief Executive Officer - 12/2015 – present GIGABYTE DEVELOPERS, Abia State (Nigeria) – *Part-time*

A senior executive (CEO) with sole responsibility for overseeing all client projects handled and managed by Gigabyte Developers as a notable fast-growing software development company in the southeast established to create first class, high quality, low cost, easy to use products that incorporate top class technologies for every single individual.

### Responsible for:

- Managing the development team.
- Providing statistical and performance feedback illustrated in charts.
- Coaching and administering performance reviews for proper skill improvement.

### Highlights:

- Successfully completed 27 projects.
- Completed development of 9 mobile applications within 18 months.
- Over 65 happy clients in a period of 4 years.
- Over 10,000 people make use of our software solutions directly or indirectly.

# Bioresources and Research Intern - 03/2016 to 10/2016 NATIONAL ROOT CROPS RESEARCH INSTITUTE, Umudike, Abia State (Nigeria)

Industrial training and research internship on bioresources.

#### Responsible for:

- Worked on several research projects.
- Providing statistical and performance data illustrated in charts.
- Cooperated with colleagues to develop a thesis on the utility of bioresources in modern-day biotechnology.

# Chief Information Officer - 10/2019 – present OCTOFI, Anambra State (Nigeria)

Octofi is a Wireless Internet Service Provider that provides fast and reliable internet service to individuals, homes and offices via WiFi.

## **Highlighted Projects**

#### - SONSHUB MOBILE

It is a mobile application for streaming and downloading gospel media contents. **Technologies Used**: Android Studio, Kotlin, Java, RxJava, RxAndroid, Android Jetpack

#### FIREFILES

FireFiles is an all-in-one (AIO) file management tool for mobile.

Technologies Used: Android Studio, Java, RxJava, Dagger

### - COMETOTP (OTP Authenticator for Android)

CometOTP implements Time-based One-time Passwords (TOTP) like specified in RFC 6238 and HMAC-based One-time Passwords (HOTP) algorithms to generate 2-Step Verification codes on your phone.

Technologies Used: Android Studio, Kotlin, Java, OpenPGP, HOTP, TOTP

### ABIA STATE JUDICIARY HIGH COURT (Probate Division)

\_

Technologies Used: PHP, Laravel Link: <a href="https://abiaprobate.com">https://abiaprobate.com</a>

### - THE STRAIGHT CHILD FOUNDATION (Charity NGO Website)

The Straight Child Foundation is a non-profit organization with the focus of advocacy and improved care for childhood deformities and disabilities. Due to the high incidence in the society, the organization focuses on Cerebral Palsy and Clubfoot.

Technologies Used: PHP, WordPress, AMP, jQuery, Google Analytics, Javascript

**Link**: https://thestraightchildfoundation.org

### - ISMILEBECAUSEYOUSMILE (Charity NGO Website)

ISmileBecauseYouSmile is a non-profit organization founded in December 2017 by Ekechi Ikechukwu Godspower and Nwokem Festus, borne out of the growing number and needs of people who have no access to quality life and living/working on the streets. The organization officially began in January 2018.

Technologies Used: PHP, WordPress, AMP, jQuery, Google Analytics, Javascript, Nginx

Link: <a href="https://ismilebecauseyousmile.org">https://ismilebecauseyousmile.org</a>

#### OBAGO MEDIA (Entertainment/Media Premier Agency Website)

ObagoMedia is an agency that specializes in creating, rebranding, managing, and maintaining brands. It is an agency focused on proper positioning of brands to establish a competitive edge. **Technologies Used**: PHP, Wordpress, AMP, Analytics, Javascript, Nginx, WordPress Jetpack

Link: https://obagomedia.com

## Other Projects

Some other projects I worked on can be found here (including SonsHub Mobile, CometOTP and FireFiles): <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/dev?id=4617962611760843834">https://play.google.com/store/apps/dev?id=4617962611760843834</a>

### Education

**NNAMDI AZIKIWE UNIVERSITY**, NIGERIA Bachelor's Degree in Botany (July, 2019)

### Certifications

**DIGITAL MARKETING**, GOOGLE Certificate issued by Google (June, 2019)

Cert ID: EL4W2LAV6

**ANALYTICS**, GOOGLE

Certificate issued by Google Skillshop (May, 2020 – May, 2021)

Completion ID: 49895602

ADS SEARCH, GOOGLE

Certificate issued by Google Skillshop (May, 2020 – May, 2021)

Completion ID: <u>49891218</u>

**DISPLAY & VIDEO 360, GOOGLE** 

Certificate issued by Google Skillshop (May, 2020 – May, 2021)

Completion ID: **49909629** 

SEARCH ADS 360, GOOGLE

Certificate issued by Google Skillshop (May, 2020 – May, 2021)

Completion ID: 49908705

**CAMPAIGN MANAGER**, GOOGLE

Certificate issued by Google Skillshop (May, 2020 – May, 2021)

Completion ID: **49897032** 

**CREATIVE CERTIFICATION, GOOGLE** 

Certificate issued by Google Skillshop (May, 2020)

Completion ID: **49897053** 

## Personal Details

DATE OF BIRTH: 27<sup>th</sup> May, 1998

LANGUAGES: English, Igbo, Spanish

ADDRESS: 40, Nnokwa Street, World Bank Housing Estate, Umuahia, Abia State